Guide to the Peter Xavier Smith Papers, 1860-1951 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Peter Xavier Smith papers 1860-1951 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Smith, Peter Xavier.
12.4 linear feet Extent: 12,905 Items
Peter Xavier Smith was a member of a Catholic family living in Norfolk, Virginia. Chiefly personal correspondence centering around a Catholic family from Norfolk, Va. Many of the letters concern student life and events at Georgetown University. There are scattered letters from U.S. Congressmen.
RL.01218
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Peter Xavier Smith Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1956 and 1959.
Collection Overview
Chiefly personal correspondence centering around a Catholic family from Norfolk, Va. Many of the letters concern student life and events at Georgetown University. There are scattered letters from U.S. Congressmen.
Subject Headings
Georgetown University -- History; Georgetown University -- Student life; Jesuits -- Education -- History -- 19th century; Catholics -- Virginia -- Correspondence; College students -- Correspondence; Domestic relations -- United States -- History -- 19th century; Catholic universities and colleges -- Social aspects; Norfolk (Va.) -- History; Virginia -- History; Washington (D.C.) -- History; Smith family
Contents of Collection
- The Peter Xavier Smith Papers, 1860-1951 and undated, (31 boxes)
  Collection largely consists of personal correspondence regarding Christianity at Georgetown University, Washington D.C.
  - Correspondence, 1860-1881 Sept. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1881 Oct.-1883 June (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1883 July-1885 Sept. (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1885 Oct.-1889 June (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1889 July-1891 May (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1891 June-1892 Sept. (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, 1892 Oct.-1894 Oct. (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1894 Nov.-1896 May (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, 1896 June-1897 Oct. (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, 1897 Nov.-1899 Oct. (Box 10)
  - Correspondence, 1899 Nov.-1901 July (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, 1901 Aug.-1902 Oct. (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, 1902 Nov.-1904 July (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1904 Aug.-1906 Jan. (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, 1906 Feb.-1907 Dec. (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, 1908 Jan.-1910 Aug. 15 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, 1910 Aug. 16-1912 Jan. (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, 1912 Feb.-1913 Aug. 14 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, 1913 Aug. 16-1915 Aug. 16 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, 1915 Aug. 17-1918 Dec. (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, 1919 Jan.-1921 Aug. (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, 1921 Sept.-1924 Dec. (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, 1925 Jan.-1930 Dec. (Box 23)
  - Correspondence, 1931 Jan.-1950 Sept. (Box 24)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 25)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 26)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 27)
  - Invitations and thank you notes, 1877-1909 (Box 27)
  - Invitations and thank you notes, 1910-1929 (Box 28)
  - Invitations and thank you notes, 1930-1944 and undated (Box 29)
  - Legal papers, 1866-1919 (Box 29)
  - Legal papers, 1920-1941 and undated (Box 30)
  - Greeting cards, 1891-1935 (Box 30)
  - Photographs (Box 30)
  - Catholic devotionals (Box 30)
  - Greeting cards, 1936-1951 (Box 31)
  - Poetry (Box 31)
  - School records (Box 31)
  - Writings (Box 31)